David Limier

Katy, Texas, United States dhawud@gmail.com +13464640987

linkedin.com/in/david-limier

Summary

I have been in the IT world for the last 20 years going through several aspects of this universe. Computer maintenance, network administration, web development, virtual reality tour, plugin development, and now flutter development for mobile, web and embedded.

Experience

SOFTWARE ENGINEER - FLUTTER WEB3 DEVELOPER



Digihost Technologies Jan - 2023 - Now

Developing Web3 application with Flutter SDK.

- Architecture
- · CI/CD
- Navigation
- Push notification
- · GCP Firebase backend
- REST JWT Auth
- Store publication (AppStore / PlayStore)
- · Feature release
- Probleme solving

SOFTWARE ENGINEER - FLUTTER LEAD APPLICATION ARCHITECT



Dedalus Jan 2022 - Jan 2023 (1 year 1 month)

Flutter lead / former for the new PatientApp:

- Architectural design of the application: Domain Driven Design Web / Responsive / PWA / io ready
- Environment integration
- External component library fitting Figma model
- Url based navigation with deep link capability Authentication: Keycloak / OpenID
- State management
- Dependency injection
- Optimized lifecycle and memory usage
- · Localization and internationalization
- REST API communication and Serialization
- Implementation of white labeling: Server Driven UI
- Dynamic UI, per client customization of : Fonts, Colors, Layout, Buttons, Titles, Icons, etc.
- Integration of: FHIR Objects / DICOM Viewer

FLUTTER LEAD ARCHITECT AT REVOLT GAME



Total rework of the 3 years code base:

- · Implementing new architecture (Clean Architecture) Injections, navigation, state management
- API communication and Serialization. DTO + Entities Implementation of brand new UI

The issues solved were: Performance, Maintainability, Modularity and reducing test phase length.

FLUTTER LEAD SOFTWARE DEVELOPER - FLUTTER INSTRUCTOR AT XEFI ACADEMY



XEFI Oct 2019 - Jun 2021 (1 year 9 months)

I participated in the entire development of 6 applications, including 3 as a team leader. I was also the relay of the hierarchy for the follow-up of project progress and the progress of the developers. My role was to make sure to improve the overall production of the developers and to train those who needed it. I was also a Flutter trainer at the XEFI Academy.

- Application architecture
- · Technical specifications
- Distribution and follow-up of tasks
- · Creation of sprints and animation of daily meetings Establishment of code conventions
- Code review
- · Responsible for publication on stores

REVIT PLUGIN DEVELOPMENT / B.I.M MODELING & 3D RENDERING



Unanime Architectes
Dec 2018 - Oct 2019 (11 months)

- · Autodesk Revit SDK plugin development.
- Autodesk Revit automation for B.I.M modeling and rapport.

DIRECTOR

id2ink

Sep 2007 - Dec 2017 (10 years 4 months)

Company specialized in mobile game development and architectural 3D visit with Unity. From conception and B.I.M modeling, to virtual reality tour.

SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR

Giga.net Casablanca Jul 2003 - Sep 2003 (3 months)

Assembly, maintenance and installation of the network of 300 workstations of the Giga.net Casablanca cybercafé.

COMPUTER TECHNICIAN



XEFI Mar 2003 - Jun 2003 (4 months)

End of study internship in computer maintenance.

3iS

Education

3iS Executive

Bachelor's degree, Web Development Oct 2003 - Jun 2005



Studio M

Bachelor's degree, Game Development Sep 2010 - Jun 2011



3iS Executive

BTS, Computer Maintenance Sys Admin Sep 2002 - Jun 2003



George W Hewlett High School Graduate, General Studies Jan 2001 - Sep 2001

Licenses & Certifications

Bachelor's degree, Web Development - French Level 6 3iS Executive license id: 82690484569

Skills

Flutter • Leadership • Software Architectural Design • Software Deployment • Mobile Application Development • Android Application Development • iOS Application Development • Web Application Development • Dart • Go • Agile Methodologies • Git • English • French